<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>VoidStar Podcast</title>
    <link>http://www.voidstarpodcast.com</link>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.mycpu.org/images/voidstar.png</url>
      <title>VoidStar Podcast</title>
      <link>http://www.voidstarpodcast.com</link>
    </image>
    <description>
      VoidStar Podcast is series where we talk to the top class achievers in tech and take a peek at the secrets to their excellence.
      Ever wondered how the top achievers got that good? Are they gifted people with extra-terrestrial abilities or are they mere mortals who share several drawbacks with the rest of us? In this podcast, I talk to top class achievers in tech and try to uncover any patterns in their habits, routines and approach. The interview format is an informal conversation with the guest for anywhere between 45 minutes to 90 minutes. My aim is to have a podcast that helps developers learn a new trick, be motivated to solve an important problem or simply do a bit more with your day. Please Subscribe.
    </description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Manoj Rao copyright 2017</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mycpu.org/images/voidstar_podcast.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 06:00:00 PDT</lastBuildDate>
    <itunes:author>Manoj Rao</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary>
      VoidStar Podcast is series where we talk to the top class achievers in tech and take a peek at the secrets to their excellence.
      A bit more: http://www.mycpu.org/about-interviews/
    </itunes:summary>
    <itunes:subtitle>VoidStar Podcast is series where we talk to the top class achievers in tech and take a peek at the secrets to their excellence</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>Manoj Rao</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>mail@mycpu.org</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:keywords>
      linux, kernel, developers, java, android, business, entrpreneurship, tech, interview, top-class, software, development, coding, source code, open source, hacks, hacking
    </itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:image href="http://www.mycpu.org/images/voidstar.png"/>
    <rawvoice:rating>TV-G</rawvoice:rating>
    <rawvoice:location>San Jose, California</rawvoice:location>
    <rawvoice:frequency>Monthly</rawvoice:frequency>
    <itunes:category text="Technology"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 06:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>VSP-001: Change The World, While Having Fun - with GKH of Linux Kernel</title>
      <link>
	http://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Greg+Kroah-Hartman.mp3
      </link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 16:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <description>
	Welcome to the Void Star Podcast Series. This episode contains my conversation with Greg Kroah-Hartman. Also known as GKH in the Linux Kernel Community. He is "Mr. Linux Device Drivers". He is the current Linux kernel maintainer for the -stable branch, the staging subsystem, USB, driver core, debugfs, kref, kobject, and the sysfs kernel subsystems, Userspace I/O (co-owned), and TTY layer. He also created linux-hotplug, the udev project, and the Linux Driver Project. He is a Fellow at the Linux Foundation. He is a co-author of the most famous Linux Device Drivers (3rd Edition) book and author of Linux Kernel in a Nutshell, and used to be a contributing editor for Linux Journal.
	We talk about Greg's secrets to being so productive, his tricks to staying on top over a thousand emails per day, his favorite editor, his favorite hacks, his system for staying focused, daily habits, routines and much more. Greg, lets us in on how to get super-human amounts of work done while not even really trying.
	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-GKH
      </description>
      <enclosure url="http://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Greg+Kroah-Hartman.mp3" length="76151389" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <guid>
        http://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Greg+Kroah-Hartman.mp3
      </guid>
      <itunes:duration>79:22</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:summary>
	Welcome to the Void Star Podcast Series. This episode contains my conversation with Greg Kroah-Hartman. Also known as GKH in the Linux Kernel Community. He is "Mr. Linux Device Drivers". He is the current Linux kernel maintainer for the -stable branch, the staging subsystem, USB, driver core, debugfs, kref, kobject, and the sysfs kernel subsystems, Userspace I/O (co-owned), and TTY layer. He also created linux-hotplug, the udev project, and the Linux Driver Project. He is a Fellow at the Linux Foundation. He is a co-author of the most famous Linux Device Drivers (3rd Edition) book and author of Linux Kernel in a Nutshell, and used to be a contributing editor for Linux Journal.
	We talk about Greg's secrets to being so productive, his tricks to staying on top over a thousand emails per day, his favorite editor, his favorite hacks, his system for staying focused, daily habits, routines and much more. Greg, lets us in on how to get super-human amounts of work done while not even really trying.
	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-GKH
      </itunes:summary>
      <itunes:image href="http://www.mycpu.org/images/voidstar.png"/>
      <itunes:keywords>
	Interview, Podcast, VoidStar, Linux, GKH, Kernel, Device Drivers, kobj, open source, Linus, Torvalds, Coding, source code, open source, Linus, Torvalds, Coding, source code, git, debug, debugging, emacs, vim, bash, tracing, eBPF
      </itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>VSP-002: Debugging At The Deep End, One Candlelight At A Time - with Steve Rostedt of Linux Kernel</title>
      <link>
	http://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Steven+Rostedt.mp3
      </link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 16:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <description>
	Welcome to the Void Star Podcast Series. This episode contains my conversation with Steve Rostedt. Steve is a Linux Kernel Programmer and he’s one of the most prolific contributors in the Linux Kernel Community. He has authored several features in the Linux Kernel including the super popular ftrace, trace-cmd, kernelshark, localmodconfig, ktest. He’s also a key contributor to Linux’s RT scheduler.

	I try to uncover the secrets behind Steve’s ability to solve with extremely complex problems in the Linux Kernel. We discuss about a ton of topics from his favorite editor and shortcuts, shell hacks, routines, habits, books, his approach to solving complex problems, his cheat sheet to remain productive, his knack to come up with clear thoughts while debugging knotty issues. There is a huge secret that Steve lets us in on, that has helped him solve extremely complex problems in a short time while having all the fun.

	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-Steve-Rostedt
      </description>
      <enclosure url="http://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Steven+Rostedt.mp3" length="187564593" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <guid>
	http://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Steven+Rostedt.mp3
      </guid>
      <itunes:duration>78:09</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:summary>
	Welcome to the Void Star Podcast Series. This episode contains my conversation with Steve Rostedt. Steve is a Linux Kernel Programmer and he’s one of the most prolific contributors in the Linux Kernel Community. He has authored several features in the Linux Kernel including the super popular ftrace, trace-cmd, kernelshark, localmodconfig, ktest. He’s also a key contributor to Linux’s RT scheduler.

	I try to uncover the secrets behind Steve’s ability to solve with extremely complex problems in the Linux Kernel. We discuss about a ton of topics from his favorite editor and shortcuts, shell hacks, routines, habits, books, his approach to solving complex problems, his cheat sheet to remain productive, his knack to come up with clear thoughts while debugging knotty issues. There is a huge secret that Steve lets us in on, that has helped him solve extremely complex problems in a short time while having all the fun.

	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-Steve-Rostedt
      </itunes:summary>
      <itunes:image href="http://www.mycpu.org/images/voidstar.png"/>
      <itunes:keywords>
	Interview, Podcast, VoidStar, Linux, Steve Rostedt, Kernel, ftrace, trace-cmd, scheduler, real-time, RT, RTLinux, RT scheduler, open source, Linus, Torvalds, Coding, source code, git, debug, debugging, emacs, vim, bash, tracing, eBPF
      </itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>VSP-003: How to Start Small and Win Big - with James Gosling, the Father of Java - Part I</title>
      <link>
	https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+James+Gosling_PART_I.mp3
      </link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 10:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <description>
	Welcome to the [Void Star Podcast Series](http://www.mycpu.org/about-interviews). This episode contains my conversation with James Gosling, the Father of Java. James Gosling has made significant contributions in the field of Computer Science, while he is most famous for inventing the Java Programming Language, he has contributed immensely by building several tools, compilers, email clients, window managers and tons of other utilities. He has worked recently on 'Wave Glider', the autonomous ocean robots and now he's working on making Cloud Computing even better. In a sense, if there was something path-breaking happening in tech, James was around! What's his secret?

	In this first part in two episode series, we talk about his early years as a student during which he may or may not have faked his age to get access to computers to practice programming, the true story behind the motivation for Java Language, his experiences programming the Ocean Robots, his take on A.I. and ramifications on our future.

	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-James-Gosling
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+James+Gosling_PART_I.mp3" length="26140658" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <guid>
	https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+James+Gosling_PART_I.mp3
      </guid>
      <itunes:duration>27:07</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:summary>
	Welcome to the [Void Star Podcast Series](http://www.mycpu.org/about-interviews). This episode contains my conversation with James Gosling, the Father of Java. James Gosling has made significant contributions in the field of Computer Science, while he is most famous for inventing the Java Programming Language, he has contributed immensely by building several tools, compilers, email clients, window managers and tons of other utilities. He has worked recently on 'Wave Glider', the autonomous ocean robots and now he's working on making Cloud Computing even better. In a sense, if there was something path-breaking happening in tech, James was around! What's his secret?

	In this first part in two episode series, we talk about his early years as a student during which he may or may not have faked his age to get access to computers to practice programming, the true story behind the motivation for Java Language, his experiences programming the Ocean Robots, his take on A.I. and ramifications on our future.

	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-James-Gosling
      </itunes:summary>
      <itunes:image href="http://www.mycpu.org/images/voidstar.png"/>
      <itunes:keywords>
	Interview, Podcast, VoidStar, Java, Emacs, Java, Robots, Oceanic Robots, Robotics, Software, Design Patterns, Plugins, Compass, IMU, Sensors, Magnetometer
      </itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>VSP-004: How to playfully toy with big ideas - with Laurent Pinchart </title>
      <link>
	https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Laurent+Pinchart.mp3
      </link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 07:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
      <description>
	Welcome to the [Void Star Podcast Series](http://www.mycpu.org/about-interviews). This episode contains my conversation with Laurent Pinchart.
	If you searched Laurent on the Internet:
	"Laurent Pinchart has been a Linux kernel developer since 2001. He has written media-related Linux drivers for consumer and embedded devices and is one of the V4L core developers. Laurent is the founder and owner of Ideas on board, a company specialized in embedded Linux design and development. He has given Linux kernel-related talks at the FOSDEM, LPC and ELC. He currently works with the Renesas Linux kernel team where he develops a wide range of embedded drivers including DRM/KMS and V4L."

 His work in V4L, fbdev, DRM/KMS, UVC, and others have made it convenient, in some cases just possible, to build products that include cameras on Linux Systems. As always, we try to find out what makes Laurent tick, the tools he uses, how he approaches problem solving, how he manages email overload and stress.

	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-Laurent-Pinchart
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Laurent+Pinchart.mp3" length="56427725" type="audio/mpeg"/>

      <guid>
	https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/voidstarpodcast/Season+1/Void+Star+Podcast+-+Laurent+Pinchart.mp3
      </guid>
      <itunes:duration>58:46</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:summary>
	Welcome to the [Void Star Podcast Series](http://www.mycpu.org/about-interviews). This episode contains my conversation with Laurent Pinchart. Laurent is not your regular Kernel Hacker (if there's such a thing..) He has worked from a very young age on several critical projects such as V4L, fbdev, DRM/KMS, UVC, and others. These projects have made it convenient, in some cases just possible, to build products that include cameras, smart displays, and other multimedia devices on Linux Systems. As always, we try to find out what makes Laurent tick, the tools he uses, how he approaches problem solving, how he manages email overload and stress.

	You can also visit: http://www.mycpu.org/interview-with-Laurent-Pinchart
      </itunes:summary>
      <itunes:image href="http://www.mycpu.org/images/voidstar.png"/>
      <itunes:keywords>
	Interview, Podcast, VoidStar, Linux, Laurent, USB, Camera, Multimedia, UVC, Kernel, display, smart devices, kidwiz, wizard, genius
      </itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>

  </channel>	      
</rss>
